Guide to the Leopold Haimson papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series IV: Strikes Project, 1980s
  - Subseries IV.2: Monographs and colloquium papers, 1982-1992
    - Strikes, Wars, and Revolutions in an International Perspective, (photocopy of typescript of the volume, with corrections)
      - Manuscripts:
        - Cronin, James. "Crisis of state and society in Britain, 1917-1922" (Box 71, Folder 5)
        - Lagrange, Hugues. "Strikes and the war" (Box 71, Folder 6)
        - Koenker, Diane; Rosenberg, William. "Strikes in Russia, 1917 the impact of revolution" (Box 71, Folder 7)
      - Related to the publication material: corrections, research notes (Box 71, Folder 8-10)
  - Subseries IV.3: Research Material
    Contains extensive data on strikes, elections, and censuses; raw data, coding books, methodology description, statistical analysis. See also: Series X: Research and reference materials--Subseries X.2: Drafts and research notes--Strikes: statistical section (boxes 127-128) and Subseries X.3: Materials from Soviet archives and libraries--Strikes, workers' movement, and labor statistics (boxes 142-147).
    - Research materials (Box 72-84)
- Series V: Seminars, 1948-1983
  Files contain materials of academic seminars held by various institutions and include seminar minutes and notes, manuscripts of talks and papers presented by various authors; and related correspondence. Organized in five subseries by the name of the institution.
  - Subseries V.1: Columbia University Seminars, 1967-1986
    Seminar minutes, manuscripts of talks and papers presented at seminars held by Columbia University with related correspondence
    Organized alphabetically by the subject of the seminars, then chronologically within the subject.
    - Communism:
      - 1967-1968 school year: Rigby, T.H. "Party and state and the Soviet lieadership since 1964" (Box 85, Folder 1)
        (Preliminary draft for presentation on the seminar of May 8)
      - 1968-1969 school year: Minutes of the seminars #2-6 and #9 (Box 85, Folder 2)
      - 1969-1970 school year:
        - Minutes of the seminars #1, 7, 9-12 (Box 85, Folder 3-4)
        - Papers: Barton, Allen; Bacevic, Ljiljana; Pantic, Dragomir. "Communications intake and output among opinion-makers in a socialist society: the Yugoslav opinion-makers" (Box 85, Folder 3-4)
      - 1970-1971 school year: Minutes of the seminars #1-6, 11-15 (Box 85, Folder 5-6)
      - 1973 Minutes and related correspondence (January-November) (Box 85, Folder 7-8)
      - 1974 Summary of Pr. A.Rabinowitch's talk and discussion (Box 85, Folder 9)
    - Political Economy of war and peace:
      - Correspondence: Melman, Seymour - L. Haimson, 1971 (Box 85, Folder 10)
      - Papers: Peck, James. "Chinese foreign policy," October 26, 1972 (Box 85, Folder 10)
        (summary of talk)
    - Slavic History and Culture:
      - 1968-1969 school year:
        - Correspondence: Shevchenko, Ihor, 1968 (Box 85, Folder 11)
        - Minutes of the seminars #1, 2, 6, 7 (Box 85, Folder 11)
      - 1969-1970 school year:
        - Minutes of five seminars (Box 85, Folder 12-13)
        - Papers: Pritsak, Omeljan. "'Igor Tale' as an historical document" (Box 85, Folder 12-13)
      - 1970-1971 school year:
        - Minutes of 5 seminars (Box 85, Folder 14-15)
        - Papers: Alef, Gustave. "Early muscovite methods of centralization" (Box 85, Folder 14-15)
      - 1971-1972 school year:
        - Minutes of five seminars (Box 85, Folder 16)
          (contain summary of talks)
        - Papers: Belknap, Robert. "Unknown Petersburg novel by Dostoevsky" (Box 85, Folder 16)
      - 1972-1973 school year:
        - Minutes (Box 86, Folder 1-2)
        - Papers:
          - Cherniavsky, Michael
            - Discussion of Dostoevsky's articles on Belinskii in Diary of Writer, 1873 concentrating on the articles, "Old People" and "One of Our Contemporary Falsehoods" (Box 86, Folder 1-2)
            - "Political culture and the emerge of national consciousness in Russia" (Box 86, Folder 1-2)
          - Fanger, Donald. Discussion on the problem of Gogol (Box 86, Folder 1-2)
          - Haimson, Leopold. "Politics of Rural Russia, 1907-1914 and the system of the Third of June" (Box 86, Folder 1-2)
      - 1973-1974 school year:
        - Minutes (Box 86, Folder 3-6)
        - Papers:
          - Gold, David. "Contemporary applications of Marxian theory" (Box 86, Folder 3-6)
          - Raeff, Marc. "Catherine II and Blackstone" (Box 86, Folder 3-6)
          - Starr, Frederick. "Russian Empire and the printed word" (Box 86, Folder 3-6)
          - Wortman, Richard. "Composition of the Russian Legal Administration in the first half of the nineteenth century" (Box 86, Folder 3-6)
        - Related correspondence (Box 86, Folder 3-6)
      - 1976 minutes of the seminar of January 16 (Box 86, Folder 7)
      - 1977 Wortman, Richard. "Power and responsibility in the upbringing of the Nineteenth Century Russian Tsars" (Box 86, Folder 7)
        (papers)
      - 1986 mailing list, pertinent correspondence (Box 86, Folder 8)
      - Harvard University: see Russian Research Center
  - Subseries V.2: Russian Institute (Harriman Institute), 1972-1973
    Manuscripts of papers delivered at the seminars in 1972-1973 with related correspondence. Arranged chronologically.
    - 1972 Russian working class and the labor movement
      - Papers:
        (with related correspondence)
        - Sablinsky, Walter. "Origin and evolution of the Petition of January 9, 1905" (Box 86, Folder 9-10)
        - Zelnik, Reginald. "Gendarmes and workers in the reign of Alexander II" (Box 86, Folder 9-10)
    - 1973 Politics of urban and rural Russia
      - Papers:
        - Travis, Bruce. "Administration of the Stolypin Land Reform in Tambov Province" (Box 86, Folder 11-12)
        - Vinogradoff, Eugene (Box 86, Folder 11-12)
      - Announcements (Box 86, Folder 11-12)
  - Subseries V.3: Russian Research Center, Harvard University, 1948-1970
    Files include seminar notes and minutes. Arranged in chronological order.
    - 1948 Karpovich, M. Introductory talk, 1948 (Box 86, Folder 13)
      (minutes of Research Seminar)
    - 1961 Bromke, Adam; Drachkovitch, Milorad. "Polish and Yugoslav roads to socialism" (Box 86, Folder 14)
    - 1966
      - Blanc, Simone. "Franc-Maconnerie sous Catherine II" (Box 86, Folder 15)
      - Kahan, Arcadius. "State and the indusrial sector of the Russian economy in the Eighteenth century" (Box 86, Folder 15)
    - 1967
      - Cohen, Jerome. "Chinese views of Soviet law" (Box 86, Folder 16)
      - Inkeles, Alex. "Social development in the USSR since the Revolution" (Box 86, Folder 16)
      - Laqueur, Walter. "Western interpretations of Soviet history" (Box 86, Folder 16)
      - Montias, John. "Industrialization of Eastern Europe" (Box 86, Folder 16)
      - Nove, Alec. "NEP" (Box 86, Folder 16)
      - Pipes, Richard. "Origins of Bolshevism: the intellectual evolution of young Lenin" (Box 86, Folder 16)
    - 1968
      - Billington, James. "Role of religion in Russian culture" (Box 86, Folder 17)
      - Hollander, Paul. "Soviet and American sociology: conflict and convergence" (Box 86, Folder 17)
      - Lowenthal, Richard. "Soviet policy towards the West" (Box 86, Folder 17)
      - Struve, Gleb. "Recent Developments in Soviet literature" (Box 86, Folder 17)
    - 1969
      - Cocks, Paul. "Parti control commission revisited" (Box 86, Folder 18)
      - Katz, Zev. "Political and industrial sociology in the Soviet Union" (Box 86, Folder 18)
      - Kolkowicz, Roman. "Comparative strategies and adversary perception: and examination of some causes and sources of misperceptions in U.S.-Soviet relations" (Box 86, Folder 18)
    - 1970
      - Butler, William. "Soviet international law" (Box 86, Folder 19)
      - Dziewanowski, M.K. "Death of the Soviet regime: a study in American sovietology" (Box 86, Folder 19)
      - Kennan, George. "Marquis de Custine's travels in Russia" (Box 86, Folder 19)
      - Schwartz, Benjamin. "Sino-Soviet relations" (Box 86, Folder 19)
      - Wiles, Peter. "Communism and economic warfare" (Box 86, Folder 19)
  - Subseries V.4: University of Pennsylvania, 1982-1983
    Contains bulletins and correspondence. Not arranged.
    - Seminars on the history of Russian society in the Twentieth century, 1982-1983 (Box 86, Folder 20)
      (bulletins and correspondence)
  - Subseries V.5: Unidentified Seminar
    Contains typescript of talk delivered by M. Temkina and of the following discussion.
    - M. Temkina's talk and discussion (Box 86, Folder 21)
- Series VI: Colloquia and Conferences, 1975-1991
  This series comprises papers by various authors presented at colloquia and conferences, Haimson's notes, documents and correspondence related to the organization of these academic events. Organized in chronological order. Related materials can also be found in Series IV: Strikes Project; Series VIII: Institutional Files; Series IX: Russian Files.
  - 1975 Colloquium on social history, Paris
    - Haimson's notes (Box 87, Folder 1)
    - Papers: Agulhon, Maurice. "Institution de la France bourgeoise, le Cercle (1810-1848)" (Box 87, Folder 1)
  - 1976 Round Table on European Social History, Pittsburgh
    - Papers and notes, (copies of typescripts and publications)
      - Feldman, Gerald. "Few comments and suggestions for the Round Table" (Box 87, Folder 1-A)
      - Fridenson, Patrick. "Ouvriers Francais face a l'introduction du Taylorisme" (Box 87, Folder 1-A)
      - Groh, Dieter
        - "Arbeitspapiere der Projectgruppe "Basisprozesse und Organisationsproblem" (Box 87, Folder 1-A)
        - "Some thoughts on the relationship between the intensification of work and industrial conflict n organized capitalism in Germany (1896-1914)" (Box 87, Folder 1-A)
      - Hinton, James. "Craft control and workers control: some questions" (Box 87, Folder 2)
      - Laux, James. "Commentary for the Fifth Round Table on European Social History" (Box 87, Folder 2)
      - Montgomery, David. "Whose standards? Workers and the reorganization of production in the united States, 1900-1920" (Box 87, Folder 2)
      - Mothe, Daniel. "Caracteristique du Taylorisme" (Box 87, Folder 2)
      - Moutet, Aimee. "Origines du systeme de Taylor en France. Le point de vuew patronal (1907-1914)" (Box 87, Folder 2)
      - Perrot, Michelle. "Bref commentaire pour la Table Ronde de Pittsburg" (Box 87, Folder 2)
      - Stearns, Peter. Comments on "Taylorism" for the Round Table (Box 87, Folder 2)
    - Haimson's notes, (notebook with holograph notes) (Box 87, Folder 3)
  - 1982 Colloquium in comparative labor history, Maison des Sciences de l'Homme: see Series VIII: Institutional Files--Subseries VIII.2: Columbia University--Maison des Sciences de l'Homme--Colloquium (Box 96, Folders 5-6)
  - 1986
    - Cortona colloquium. Work program and list of participants (Box 87, Folder 4)
    - NEP conference, 1986. Papers
      - Hagen, Mark von. "School of socialism": the Red Army and the peasantry, 1918-30" (Box 87, Folder 5-6)
      - Hatch, John. "Labor conflict in Moscow during the early NEP" (Box 87, Folder 5-6)
      - Koenker, Diane. "Class and consciousness in a socialist society: workers in the printing trades during NEP" (Box 87, Folder 5-6)
      - Robin, Regine. "Peasants as readers" (Box 87, Folder 5-6)
      - Weissman, Neil. "Policing the NEP countryside" (Box 87, Folder 5-6)
    - New Orleans Soviet-American Conference on Quantitative History
      - Correspondence with organizations and various persons, circular letters (Box 87, Folder 7)
      - List of participants (Box 87, Folder 7)
      - Papers: Haimson, L. and Eric Brian. "Observations on additional statistical tables and regression equations of quantitative analyses of industrial labor conflicts in Imperial Russia during the First World War: August 1914-February 1917", (typescript with holograph notes) (Box 87, Folder 7)
  - 1988 Soviet-American conference. Correspondence with various organizations and people (Box 87, Folder 8)
  - 1990
    - Leningrad colloquium "Development of the revolutionary situation in early twentieth century russia" / "Rabochii klass i revoliutsionnye situatsii v rossii v nachale XX veka", Leningrad, 3-9 June 1990
      - Program, circular letters, 1989-1990 (Box 87, Folder 9)
      - Transcript of the colloquium, 1990 (Box 87, Folder 10-11)
        (in Russian; with related correspondence)
      - Original Papers:
        - Haimson, Leopold. "Historical sources of the Revoliution of 1917 and the role of the workers' movement" (Box 87, Folder 12)
        - Wortman, Richard. "Nicholas II and the representation of autocratic power" (Box 87, Folder 12)
      - Translations of Papers:
        - Diakin, Viktor. "Vybor puti ekonomicheskogo razvitiia Rossii (konets XIX-nachalo XX vv.)" (Box 87, Folder 13)
        - Engelstein, Lora. "Polovoi vopros" i politicheskii krizis professional'noi intelligentsii posle revoliutsii 1905 g." (Box 87, Folder 13)
        - Gastrell, P. "Ekonomicheskoe i sotsial'noe razvitie Rossii v nachale XX veka" (Box 87, Folder 13)
        - MacKey, John. "Razvitie ekonomiki i regional'noe predprinimatel'stvo v poslednii period Rossiskoi imperii" (Box 87, Folder 13)
        - Wcislo, "Otnoshenie mezhdu pravitel'stvom I mestnoi vlast'iu. Stolypin i tret'eiiun'skiaq monarkhiia" (Box 87, Folder 13)
  - 1991 Paris conference. List of participants from USSR, UK, and USA (Box 87, Folder 14)
- Series VII: Editorial Activity, 1964-1974
  The series contains materials related to Haimson's work as an editor and compiler and includes drafts, notes, and corrections for The Mensheviks and project documentation, and manuscript for The Russian revolutionary tradition: an anthology. For more materials on Haimson's editorial activity see Series III: Menshevik project; Series IV: Strikes Project.
  - Mensheviks, 1974
    (drafts, notes, corrections)
    - Introduction (Box 88, Folder 1-7)
    - Revised versions (Box 88, Folder 1-7)
    - Notes, corrections (Box 88, Folder 1-7)
  - Russian Revolutionary Tradition: an Anthology, 1964
    - Project documentation: correspondence, introduction, outline, schedules, financial records, reports (Box 88, Folder 8-9)
    - Manuscripts
      (copies of off-prints and typescripts of translations)
      - "Chernyi peredel," 1880 (Box 88, Folder 10)
      - "K molodomu pokoleniiu," 1861 (Box 88, Folder 11)
      - Lemke, M. "Protsess 'Velikorusstsev'", 1908 (Box 88, Folder 12)
      - "Nasha deistvitel'nost': rabochee dvizhenie, samoderzhavie, obshchestvo s ego sloiami (dvorianstvo, krupnaia i melkaia burzhuaziia, krest'iane i rabochie) i obshchestvennaia bor'ba" (Box 88, Folder 13)
      - Programma sotsial-demokraticheskoi gruppy "Osvobozhdenie Truda", 1884 (Box 88, Folder 14)
      - Stepniak, S. "Chego nam nuzhno i nachalo kontsa," 1892 (Box 88, Folder 15)
      - Struve, Petr:
        - "Intelligentsiia i revoliutsiia," 1908-1909 (Box 88, Folder 16)
        - "Ot redaktora" (Osvobozhdenie) (Box 88, Folder 17)
        - "Theorie marxienne de l'evolution sociale: essay critique" (Box 88, Folder 18)
        - "Velikaia Rossiia," 1908 (Box 88, Folder 19)
      - Voitinskii, Vladimir. "Otets" (Box 88, Folder 20)
        (author aka Woytinsky, W.)
- Series VIII: Institutional Files, 1956-1990s
  Institutional materials accrued by Haimson during his work at the University of Chicago, Columbia University, and the Harriman Institute make up this series. Subject files contain internal institutional documents and correspondence, Haimson's correspondence with various organizations, grant applications and proposals, correspondence with publishers of his books, and materials regarding the Menshevik project. Organized into two subseries.
  - Subseries VIII.1: Chicago University Files, 1956-1966
    This subseries includes subject files related to Haimson's work at Chicago University. Files organized in alphabetical order by subject.
    - Columbia University, 1960-1964
      - Columbia Travel Service, 1961 (Box 89, Folder 1)
      - Program on East Central Europe, 1962 (Box 89, Folder 1)
        (Ihor Shevchenko)
      - Varia (Box 89, Folder 1)
    - Committee on Slavic Studies: see Slavic Committee
    - Grants:
      - Inter-University Committee on Travel Grants, 1956-1961 (Box 89, Folder 2)
      - Mandel Faculty, 1960-1964 (Box 89, Folder 3)
      - Social Science Research Committee, 1962 (Box 89, Folder 3)
    - History Department:
      - Memos, 1961-1962 (Box 89, Folder 4)
      - Appointments, 1960-1963 (Box 89, Folder 5)
      - General internal correspondence, 1959-1964
        - Clive, John (Box 89, Folder 6)
        - Cotton, Albert (Box 89, Folder 6)
        - Greene, Greta (Box 89, Folder 6)
        - Harris, Chauncy (Box 89, Folder 6)
        - Johnson, Walter (Box 89, Folder 6)
        - McNeill, William (Box 89, Folder 6)
        - Unidentified (Box 89, Folder 6)
      - Class lists and rosters, 1957-1959, 1964 (Box 89, Folder 7)
      - Reading lists for Russian history courses, undated, 1962 (Box 89, Folder 8)
    - Library:
      - Correspondence on Slavic acquisitions and exchange, 1959-1965
        - Anderle, Josef (Box 89, Folder 9-13)
        - Fussler, Herman (Box 89, Folder 9-13)
        - Prague (Box 89, Folder 9-13)
        - Varia (Box 89, Folder 9-13)
      - Lists for exchange (Box 89, Folder 14)
      - Reports and memos on book exchanges and purchases in Russia, 1961-1962 (Box 89, Folder 15)
      - Sabo-Slavic books catalog (Box 89, Folder 16)
        (See also: Series III: Menshevik project--Subseries III.1: Project records--Sub-subseries III.1.1: Correspondence--Library, Box 15, Folders 12-13)
    - Office of the Dean of the Division of the Social Sciences, 1961-1964 (Box 89, Folder 17)
    - Russian Civilization Group, 1958-1962 (Box 89, Folder 18-19)
      (minutes, letters, readings lists, term papers requirements, course planning, notes)
    - Russian Program:
      - Proposals, 1959-1961 (Box 90, Folder 1)
      - Ford negotiations files:
        - Correspondence, 1960-1961 (Box 90, Folder 2)
        - Proposals, drafts, 1960-1961 (Box 90, Folder 3-6)
    - Slavic Committee, 1962 (Box 90, Folder 7-8)
      (memos, proposals)
    - Students
      (personal files, recommendations, related correspondence)
      - General, 1959-1965 (Box 90, Folder 9)
      - Personal files, 1959-1966 (Box 90, Folder 10-14)
  - Subseries VIII.2: Columbia University Files, 1966-1990s
    This subseries includes subject files related to Haimson's work at Columbia University. Files arranged alphabetically by subject.
    - File index (Box 91, Folder 1)
    - American Council of Learned Societies (ACLS), 1960-1987
      - Grant applications and correspondence (Box 91, Folder 2)
        (See also: Series III: Menshevik Project--Subseries III.1: Project records--Sub-subseries III.1.1: Correspondence--Menshevik interviews correspondence, Box 15, Folder 14)
    - American Historical Association: Correspondence on American-Soviet conferences and Soviet historians visits, 1970-1980
      - ACLS (Box 91, Folder 3)
      - Arden House (Box 91, Folder 3)
      - Harvard University - Russian Research Center (Box 91, Folder 3)
      - IREX (Box 91, Folder 3)
    - American Philosophical Society: Correspondence, 1972-1977 (Box 91, Folder 4)
    - Artran Foundation: Grant proposal and correspondence, 1980, 1983 (Box 91, Folder 5)
    - Bakhmeteff Committee (formerly: Humanities Committee): Grant proposal and application from the Humanities Fund, 1971, 1971, 1977 (Box 91, Folder 6)
    - Bibliographic Information: lists of newspapers and archives, 1971-1977 (Box 91, Folder 7)
    - Bradley Foundation: see Lynde and Harry Bradley Foundation
    - Cambridge University Press: see Series I: Correspondence--Subseries I.4: Subject correspondence--Sub-subseries I.4.3: Publishers, Box 11, Folders 5-6
    - Center for Advanced Study in Behavioral Sciences, 1976-1985 (Box 91, Folder 8)
    - Center for the Social Sciences, 1986 (Box 91, Folder 9)
    - Columbia University crisis of 1968 Internal correspondence, memos, circular letters (Box 91, Folder 10)
    - Conference on 1917 Circular letters, drafts of documents, 1976 (Box 91, Folder 11)
    - Department of History: see History Department
    - Ecole des Hautes Etudes Sociales et Economiques, 1980-1987 (Box 91, Folder 12)
    - Ecole Pratique des Hautes Etudes: Correspondence, applications, research notes, 1972-1977 (Box 91, Folder 13)
      (See also: Series I: Correspondence--Subseries I.2: General correspondence--Heller, C. (Box 3, Folder 10); Series III: Menshevik project--Subseries III.1: Project records--Sub-subseries III.1.1: Correspondence-- Ecole Pratique des Hautes Etudes (Box 15, Folder 1); Other files of Menshevik project correspondence)
    - Employment announcements, 1966-1987 (Box 91, Folder 14)
      (job openings and recommendations. Arranged in chronological order)
    - Faculty Elections Bureau, 1970 (Box 92, Folder 1)
    - Faculty Peace Action, 1970-1971 (Box 92, Folder 2-3)
    - Ford Foundation, 1965-1990 (Box 92, Folder 4-5)
      (correspondence, grant proposals and applications)
    - Graduate School of Arts and Sciences, 1986, 1994 (Box 92, Folder 6)
      (memos, letters)
    - Guggenheim Memorial Foundation, 1963-1965 (Box 92, Folder 7)
      (John Simon Guggenheim Memorial Foundation. Correspondence, research proposal, background information)
    - Harriman Institute (Russian Institute):
      (See also files on Menshevik Project funding of 1961-1968 in: Series III: Menshevik Project--Subseries III.1: Project Records--Sub-subseries: III.1.4: Grant Files, Box 18, Folder 18)
      - Foundation of the Harriman Institute, 1982 (Box 92, Folder 8-9)
        (documents, clippings, notes)
      - Business plan, 1982-1986 (Box 92, Folder 10)
      - Memoranda, 1966-1994 (Box 92, Folder 11)
      - Faculty and Committee meetings, 1971-1987 (Box 92, Folder 12-13)
      - Courses, 1964-1987 (Box 93, Folder 1)
      - Workshops, 1984-1992 (Box 93, Folder 2)
        (circular letters)
      - Publications, 1970-1983 (Box 93, Folder 3-6)
        (publication committee, publication reports, reading reports, correspondence)
      - Fellowships, 1971-1986 (Box 93, Folder 7)
        (announcements, recommendations, applications)
      - General correspondence, 1965-1990s (Box 93, Folder 8-10)
      - Marshall D. Shulman Dinner, 1986 (Box 93, Folder 11)
      - Printed material
        - Information packet, 1984-1985 (Box 93, Folder 12)
        - Harriman Institute newsletter, 1990s (Box 93, Folder 13)
        - Varia (Box 93, Folder 14)
    - Harvard University:
      - Department of History, 1966-1971 (Box 94, Folder 1)
      - Russian Research Center: Correspondence, memos, and fellowships applications, 1948-1971 (Box 94, Folder 2)
      - Summer School, 1966-1967 (Box 94, Folder 3)
      - Harvard-Columbia Russian Studies Fund, 1974-1982 (Box 94, Folder 4-12)
        (memoranda, correspondence, constituent documents, reports, clippings)
    - Harvard University Press: see Publishers
    - History department:
      - Appointment, 1964-1966 (Box 94, Folder 13)
        (correspondence with Robert Cross re: Haimson's appointment to Columbia)
      - General, 1966-1989
        (correspondence, memos, documents, CVs)
        - 1966-1969 (Box 94, Folder 14-15)
        - 1970-1989 (Box 95, Folder 1-2)
      - Course offerings, 1967-1968, 1982-1997 (Box 95, Folder 3)
        (course descriptions, syllabus, readings, requirements)
      - Search committee on Russian History, 1986-1987 (Box 95, Folder 4)
    - Humanities Fund: see Bakhmeteff Committee
    - Indiana University Press: see Series I: Correspondence--Subseries I.4: Subject correspondence--Sub-subseries I.4.3: Publishers (Box 11, Folder 12)